I know a jamika today we are going to
talk about the top five highest paid
programming languages according to Stack
Overflow developer survey of 2019
closure F sharp go Scala and elixir if
you are like me you maybe have never
ever heard of any of these programming
languages and that is okay because they
are very very weird these programming
languages are very good at something
called functional programming and
parallelism or concurrency functional
programming is just a different way of
thinking about your code so for example
if you look at Python or dart they're
very object oriented that means that
they have stuff called classes they have
stuff called this they have inheritance
they have extends they have all these
kind of things that is object-oriented
everything is an object and it has some
rules and whatever the same thing will
be with functional programming they have
functions they have pure functions they
have impure functions they have stuff
like state they have stuff like in
mutable and mutable state there are
different just different ways of
organizing your code the second thing is
concurrency or parallelism so for
example in the case of go the Creator
has said that they just wanted to build
a programming language a language that
takes advantage of a multi-core
processing to be able to do stuff at the
same time faster than ever before
that is concurrency and parallelism kind
of it is basically doing stuff at the
same time these languages are very good
at using threads using multi-core
processors to do things fast at the same
time which is something amazing closure
is the top highest one closure
we're gonna show you how it looks here
closure is being used to do the
diagnosis of the airplane's diagnosis
tool to diagnose how everything on the
plane is working so they made a program
they plug in the airplane in that
program that ignores is the airplane and
then it says okay this airplane comes
like that's basically what closure is
doing which is unbelievable
can you imagine that imagine if that
imagine if that program had an air
they'll be insane the second one is F
sharp F sharp was created by Microsoft
so and also was created on the with a
very good portability to the net
ecosystem that net is like a Microsoft
framework for doing stuff so F sharp is
like the faster functional way of doing
things and you can talk to that net the
applications are not so fun and when I
was researching for like who is hiring F
sharp programmers what I saw is Facebook
gaming for example was looking for F
sharp programmers the only one is go and
go is a very very popular nowadays
because go is very very sexy very easy
to learn it's not ugly at all and it's
super freakin fast so for example many
of the companies that we're running in
no jets are moving to go go is created
by Google so it's used a lot in Google
it's also used in YouTube and it's also
used for the download part of Google so
the server that handles the downloading
of files in Google that is built on go
so it's really really fast and people
are liking it because it doesn't look so
ugly the only one is color people say
that Scala is kind of like Java plus the
best features that's basically what
color will be so it's just like nice sir
functional Java Twitter for example
Twitter was created with Ruby on Rails
and eventually Ruby on Rails couldn't
handle so many people so they have to
move to something else and they moved to
Scala and the last thing my test last
time I checked
Scala was part of like 70% of the
codebase of Twitter so it's handling
pretty brief rocking well the last one
is a leak
and elixir is built on top of something
called Erlang virtual machine Erlang is
a programming language that is very good
a low latency is very good at fast speed
of transmission of data why are these
programming languages so well-paid and
should you learn them if you wanna have
a good Europe in a company what I think
in this case is that as you can see the
applications for these programming
languages are so specific and sub tiny
that I feel that the hiring pool is very
small as well as the talent pool is very
small so very few people are good are
good at closure and very few companies
need closure programmers that is the
recipe for highest paid because if
you're a good closure programmer I know
other companies out there that need only
closure programmers so they're going to
pay you really really well but should
you learn them if you are like me that
you like to get stuff done that you
don't enjoy programming for the sake of
programming that you don't have a
specific problem to solve then I would
say learn a more general-purpose
programming language such as Python or
JavaScript or C sharp or even Java in
that case not something so specific and
something so niche also the community
will be small and everything will be
small they're not bad for ramen
languages at all but it's not something
that beginners should look up to like oh
my god one day I want to be a coder
program in because that's not just not
greedy I would say definitely from the
description I gave you look into the
ones that you liked the most the ones
that you're interested in most and maybe
spend a couple of weekends learning them
to see if you like them or not because
also it can be fun it doesn't have to be
always about money it could be all about
fun thank you for watching let me know
what you think of this video let me know
what I like let me know with a comment
subscribe share to your friends be happy
it Kim G's and yourself beaming pop
everything love you bye bye